amstat.org 2004-04-22

# American Statistical Association

Privacy Statement for www.amstat.org

## Privacy Statement for www.amstat.org

Below: Choice/Opt Out | Contacting the Web Site | Cookie Information     
Correct/Update User Profile | Security and more!

This Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy. We disclose information practices below concerning:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through the web site
  2. The organization collecting the information 
  3. How the information is used 
  4. With whom the information may be shared 
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under ASA control 
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact the ASA webmaster by email at [webmaster@amstat.org](mailto:webmaster@amstat.org) or by phone, (703) 684-1221.

* * *

The American Statistical Association (ASA) has a strong commitment to privacy, balanced by a recognition that we are a public association. This statement discloses policies and procedures concerning information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: [www.amstat.org](http://www.amstat.org/). 

  * User Information 
  * Security
  * Correct/Update User Profile
  * Choice/Opt Out
  * Contacting the Web Site
  * Right to Change Privacy Statement 
  * Links to Other Sites
  * Cookie Information
  * Possible Future Privacy Policies

* * *

### User Information

Users of this Web site may differ in their access or needs. We recommend that you read this policy in its entirety to understand your and our responsibilities. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. 

The information nn this statement is summarized into two broad headings -- customer information and member information. Members who place orders should also read the customer information section. Our site uses cookies when we need to keep track from one screen to another, such as when you log in to [Members Only](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly/) using a password or when you use a shopping cart. See below for more information on cookies. 

#### Customer Information

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitors' contact information (such as name and email address) and financial information (such as account or credit card numbers). Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. Contact information from the order form is used to send orders, information about our association, and promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. This contact information is also used to get in touch with the customer when necessary. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt out section below.

#### Member Information

Members' contact information is made available through the Member Directory. Members' contact information is shared with other organizations that promote statistics or professional development of statisticians. Members may opt out of receiving future mailings or listing in the Member Directory; see the choice/opt out section below. 

### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Member personal information is behind a firewall, modifiable by each member only by password access through secure forms pages. Member Directory information is not accessible by search engines that hunt for HTML pages.

Secured Server Certificate from VeriSign, Inc. is utilized to identify your secured connection to our Web site. Personal information ("Basic Contact Information") collected through our site are entered and transmitted over Secure Socket Layer (SSL) with a maximum encryption strength of 128-bit, which creates an encrypted session between the user browser and the Web server.  
  
---|---  
  
### Correct/Update

Members can change their address and related information at [ www.amstat.org/membersonly/](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly/)

Members and other customers can send corrections to ASA by email ([asainfo@amstat.org](mailto:asainfo@amstat.org)) or by regular mail (address below).

### Choice/Opt Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of (e.g. stop or discontinue) receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database so as to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

  1. Members can visit the following URL: [https://www.amstat.org/MembersOnly](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly)
  2. Members and customers can send mail to the following postal address: 
Webmaster, American Statistical Association, 1429 Duke St., Alexandria, VA 22314-3402, USA 

### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact 

Webmaster   
American Statistical Association   
1429 Duke St.   
Alexandria, VA 22314-3402, USA

Telephone 888-231-3473 or 703-684-1221 [webmaster@amstat.org](mailto:webmaster@amstat.org)

Also you can contact Customer Service with any questions about ASA: [asainfo@amstat.org](mailto:asainfo@amstat.org). Street address and phone number are the same as above.

### Right to Change Privacy Statement

This policy may be revised over time as new features are added to the Web site. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Please check this site for information about revisions to our privacy policy.

###  **Links to Other Sites**

This site contains links to other sites. The American Statistical Association is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other Web sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects your personally identifiable information.

* * *

### Cookie Information

The American Statistical Association uses cookies on this Web site, www.amstat.org, when we need to keep track from one screen to another, such as when you log in to [Members Only](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly/) using a password or when you use a shopping cart. A "magic cookie" is a datum sent by our Web server to your Web browser, stored in RAM while your browser is in use, or in a file called something like "cookies" on your machine. Cookies helps keep track of your Web session with www.amstat.org. 

Cookies store information that the Web site uses. Some of this information (e.g., last visited Web site, your IP address, the browser and version you use) are available to ANY Web site you visit, regardless of your security settings. This information is built into the Internet and its communication methods and protocols. Generally, you cannot stop this information from going out. Other information is gathered by user input, typically by forms. In other words, a cookie will not know your home phone number unless you give that information to a form or other input device on a Web site.

Some sites are now using cookies to differentiate between repeat users and new users rather than going by general "hit" statistics, which are not very specific. In this way, a Web site administrator can form a clearer picture of how the site is used. Cookies cannot access any other file on your computer. Cookies created by one site will only work with that specific site. Site A, for example, cannot read cookies generated by Site B and then use that information for purposes for which it was not originally intended.

It is the express policy of www.amstat.org that data generated by cookies and related databases will be used only in aggregate form for the purpose of improving the site and site-related services for users. Information from individual cookies will only be accessible to Web site administrators within the ASA office. The aggregated data compiled via cookies and related databases are considered confidential and will not be provided to entities outside of the organization under any circumstances. Our cookies crumble after 24 hours. 

You can manage cookies if you edit your browser Preferences/Internet Options (check the Advanced features). You can also periodically remove the cookies file on your machine. However, if you disallow cookies, you may disable access to advanced functionality on our Web site (members: see next paragraph). For more information on cookies, consult the Help button of your browser or visit other information sources such as the [EPIC Cookies Page](http://www.epic.org/privacy/internet/cookies/) or [Cookie Central](http://www.cookiecentral.com/). See also the [list of cookies pages at Texas Tech University](http://www.tltc.ttu.edu/Library/cookies.htm). 

**ASA members** : Cookies are NOT used to verify your authority to access the [Members Only](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly/) area of our website. However, they ARE used once the authorization has been verified to allow you access to each of page in [Members Only](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly/), and access to secure committee or other official pages where you serve as an officer. In other words, your password is not contained in a cookie, but your authority level is. Your authority to view each page in the member's area is verified at the time you access that page. While you can access the [Members Only](https://www.amstat.org/membersonly/) area of our website without cookies, the quality of your session may be reduced if they are prohibited.  

* * *

### Possible Future Privacy Policies

The policies below are in development, pending use of this web site for other activities that might affect privacy. If you have any comments, please feel free to share them with [webmaster@amstat.org](mailto:webmaster@amstat.org).

#### Surveys

Our online surveys may ask visitors for contact information (such as email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). Responses are kept confidential and are not provided to any third party. If the survey is at the request of a third party who will receive the information, the survey will prominently identify the name and link to their privacy policy. We may use contact date from our surveys to send the user information about our association. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt out section. Demographic and profile data may be collected at our site. This information is shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis.

#### Public Forums

This site may make chat rooms, list servers, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its members. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

This page was constructed with assistance from [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/). However, the American Statistical Association (ASA) no longer is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. 

* * *

Copyright | Privacy Statement | Disclaimer  
© 2003 American Statistical Association. All Rights Reserved.  
Upgrading to the latest version of browser software [Microsoft](http://www.microsoft.com/windows/ie/), [Netscape](http://www.netscape.com/download/), or [Opera](http://www.opera.com/download) may enhance your online experience.
